<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Vaceslav Kanukov</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Vaceslav Kanukov</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 10:41:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://christianbarnettre.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Good and the Bad of Christian Fundamentalism</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/89680062-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 10:41:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/89680062-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</guid><description>The term "fundamentalist" is one that can have both positive and negative connotations when applied to Christians. This article will explore some of the good aspects of Christian fundamentalism as well as some of the negative ramifications which are sometimes associated with this movement within Christianity.
Christian fundamentalism was born out of a reaction to various modernist trends that threatened traditional Christian beliefs in the late nineteenth century and early twentieth century ^{[1]}.</description></item><item><title>Is it My Responsibility to Help the Widows and Orphans?</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/69063294-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 19:44:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/69063294-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</guid><description>The question of whether it is your responsibility to help widows and orphans has many aspects. In this article, we will explore several religious perspectives, look at societal roles and expectations, and understand why caring for these vulnerable groups is important. Ultimately, the decision to extend a helping hand lies with each individual, but knowledge on the subject can help you make an informed choice.
Religious Perspectives Many religions see caring for widows and orphans as a moral duty.</description></item><item><title>How Should Christians Approach Progress in Technology?</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/63450194-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 11:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/63450194-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</guid><description>The word “technology” refers to the use of scientific knowledge for practical purposes. It is often seen as something good, but is this always so? As Christians, how do we determine whether a technology is morally acceptable? What guidelines do we follow when considering technology? This article explores these questions in order to provide some wisdom for approaching progress in technology from a Christian perspective.
Evaluating Technology Through Biblical Principles As believers who desire to be conformed to Christ (Romans 8:29), we are called to live our lives according to the principles found in Scripture.</description></item><item><title>Self-Care: Selfish Habit or Holy Endeavor?</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/64190647-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 22:53:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/64190647-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</guid><description>The phrase "self-care" has entered into the Christian community vernacular over the last few years, causing some to question whether it represents a biblical practice or an ungodly self-absorption. As with any topic, evaluating Scripture is crucial for defining whether something aligns with God's plan and purpose for our lives as Christians. In this reflection paper, we will explore the concept of self-care biblically, historically, practically and spiritually, in order to decide if it is a selfish habit or a holy endeavor.</description></item><item><title>Why Pastors Struggle to Ask for Help (And How to Get Past It)</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/85509218-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 18:04:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/85509218-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</guid><description>As a pastor myself, I know that many of us find it difficult to ask for help—even when we desperately need it. It isn’t easy to admit vulnerability or acknowledge deficiencies in our abilities. However, doing so is essential if we want to effectively serve our congregations and avoid burnout. Here are some reasons why pastors struggle to ask for help along with suggestions for overcoming these obstacles.
Fear of Appearing Weak Many pastors feel compelled to maintain an image of strength and competence within their church communities.</description></item><item><title>Why People Are Losing Their Religion (and How the Church Can Respond)</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/98206190-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 14:50:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/98206190-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</guid><description>The claim that people are “losing their religion” has become a frequent subject of debate in both popular culture and within academic circles. This phenomenon is not new but seems to have taken on new dimensions in recent decades. Concerns about religious decline stretch across denominations and cultures, leading various Christian traditions to ponder how best to respond.
In this white paper, we will explore the multiple dimensions of religious decline, examine the possible reasons behind it, and propose ways forward for church leaders and congregations.</description></item><item><title>4 Keys to Building Confidence in God When Life Falls Apart</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/90850208-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 08:04:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/90850208-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</guid><description>If you're facing overwhelming circumstances, such as an unexpected loss, deep frustration with God, or a series of difficult challenges, it's only natural to have doubts, worries, and struggles. Your heart longs to find a way back to confidence in God but it seems elusive right now. What can you do to regain that trust and renew your relationship with Him when life falls apart?
Below are four keys to help you build trust and confidence in God during dark times:</description></item><item><title>Why Should Christians Evaluate What Their Lives Are Built On?</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/78163968-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 01:12:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/78163968-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</guid><description>Christians are called to evaluate what their lives are built on in order to ensure that their foundation is firmly established on the biblical principles and teachings of Jesus Christ. This process of examination helps to build a strong spiritual foundation, identifying areas where improvements may be needed, and ensuring we are walking in accordance with God's will for our lives.
Building on the Foundation of Christ The Bible presents Jesus Christ as the cornerstone upon which believers should construct their lives (1 Corinthians 3:11; Ephesians 2:20-22).</description></item><item><title>Why the Church Should Take Responsibility for Its Liberties and Freedoms</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/44650184-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 09:11:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/44650184-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</guid><description>In every generation, there is an inherent call on the Body of Christ to examine and defend its liberties and freedoms. The spiritual realm is constantly in conflict with the forces of darkness through which the church may be diminished or even forced into submission. Therefore, as Christians, we must understand our responsibilities in this area so as not to forfeit these benefits bestowed upon us by God.
In this article, we will explore why taking responsibility for these liberties and freedoms is vital to maintaining the integrity and effectiveness of the church both individually and corporately.</description></item><item><title>One Key Reason Why Church Consultations Fail</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/53222974-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 10:53:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/53222974-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</guid><description>In consulting with churches I have become dismayed over the numerous attempts at revitalizing or rebuilding a congregation only to see them crash back into their old, unhealthy patterns. This phenomenon happens more often than not which has led me to wonder what key factor causes these consultations to fail.
What I will highlight may be shocking to some but after three decades of observing hundreds of churches I've come to believe that one key reason why church consultations fail is because so many church leaders refuse to go through personal brokenness and surrender before God in order to experience genuine spiritual renewal.</description></item><item><title>Why Do Christians Emphasize Hell Instead of Not Being with God in Heaven?</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/22356939-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 17:18:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/22356939-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</guid><description>It is true that some Christians tend to emphasize the idea of Hell more than others. The main reason for this could be a desire to effectively communicate God’s warning against sin, thus persuading others to avoid eternal separation from Him. However, it is important to remember that not all Christians communicate the message only by focusing on Hell. Several churches and religious leaders interpret Scriptures differently when addressing God's love and ways He addresses sin.</description></item><item><title>Guilt and the Great Deception in the Christian Life</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/15121523-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 14:41:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/15121523-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</guid><description>The Christian life is often plagued by guilt, anxiety, and shame. Though the scriptures provide God’s promises of redemption, righteousness, holiness, and freedom from bondage to sin, many believers continue to struggle with feelings of unworthiness and guilt. This suggests that something more might be at play than simply a lack of belief or understanding these truths. The Bible describes this deceptive force as Satan (or the Devil) who seeks to hinder our progress in Christlikeness.</description></item><item><title>What Does Jesus Teach Us about God's End-Times Plan?</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/36516282-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 08:18:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/36516282-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</guid><description>When discussing various aspects of life, ranging from personal responsibilities to current events, we are often directed towards asking, "What does Jesus teach us?" The words of Christ provide an invaluable lens through which we may understand fundamental truths about existence, morality, and even eschatology. In this case, let's focus on understanding what Jesus teaches us concerning God's end times plan.
Parables on the Second Coming In several parables, Jesus offers insights into God's end times plan:</description></item><item><title>Why Christians Can Be Bad at Being Kind</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/60000051-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 08:43:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/60000051-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</guid><description>The Bible makes it very clear that believers in Jesus Christ should be known for their love and kindness among those around them. In fact, Jesus Himself taught that people would be able to identify Christians by the fruit they bear—with love being chief among such fruit (John 13:35). If then, one would expect believers in this day and age to be friendly, caring and considerate. However, a number of reasons can be put forward as to why this often times does not seem to be the case.</description></item><item><title>How to Actually Treat Other Believers Like Family</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/13125965-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 05:59:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/13125965-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</guid><description>A passage from Paul's letter to the Galatians has often been used as a call to treat all fellow Christians like family members. Here is Galatians 6:9-10: "Let us not become weary in doing good, for at the proper time we will reap a harvest if we do not give up. Therefore, whenever we have the opportunity, let us work for the good of all, and especially for those who belong to our family in faith.</description></item><item><title>Why Are There So Many Ideas about Heaven That Are Not Biblical?</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/84050137-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 12:41:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/84050137-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</guid><description>The concept of Heaven occupies a prominent role in human history and religious thought. However, the many ideas about Heaven are not always consistent with biblical teachings. This article explores how various cultural factors have influenced diverse understandings of Heaven beyond its original biblical context. Additionally, it examines why certain contemporary ideas may fail to align with Jesus' teach ings or apostolic revelations.
Historical Influences Shaping Perceptions of Heaven Throughout history, numerous cultures have held distinct beliefs about afterlife experiences, often predating Christianity itself.</description></item><item><title>9 Lessons for New Christians ... And Old Ones</title><link>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/76731159-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 13:04:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://christianbarnettre.github.io/posts/76731159-9-lessons-for-new-christians-and-old-ones/</guid><description>If you are new to the Christian life or just need a refresher course, here are 9 biblical truths that will strengthen your faith and help keep you focused on following Jesus Christ.
What Does It Mean To Be a Christian? A Christian is any person who has personally accepted Jesus Christ as their Lord and Savior. Their life is centered around God’s Son and what He accomplished through His life on earth.</description></item></channel></rss>